AMANULLAH ASHRAF () Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Software Design, Agile Methodology, Project Management, Software Troubleshooting, JIRA, Jenkins, GIT, Android, Linux, C++, C, Visual Studio, SQL



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Hughes Systique Corporation Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Gurgaon Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.
[Electronics/Telecommunication]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Pref. Location: Chandigarh, Delhi / NCR, Jaipur

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Software Design, Agile Methodology, Project Management, Software Troubleshooting, JIRA, Jenkins, GIT, Android, Linux, C++, C, Visual

Studio, SQL, C#

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Having 6 years of experience in programming in C and C++.

As a senior software engineer, has been involved in C++ feature development, maintenance of code and bug fixing. Domains that I have contributed in are: Test application development, Networking(OTN) and Multimedia(Sling TV).

Work Experience

Hughes Systique Corporation as Senior Software Engineer Mar 2019 to Till Date

SlingTV(March 2019 to current)

- * Description
- * Integration of C++ code with JNI for Sling Android app. Participation in basic design changes in C++ code.
- * Multiple bug fixes done needed for maintenance.
- * Participated in integrating Athena(CPP) code with UI and Platform(streamer).
- * Worked on design patterns like observer and Factory.
- * Role: Senior Engineer
- * Languages used: C++ with LINUX
- * Tools Used: Jenkins, Bitbucket, JIRA and Vim editor

HCL Infosystems Ltd. as Lead Engineer

Jul 2017 to Mar 2019

Description

- * Writing C++ applications to verify the working of ported libraries and OS.
- * Designing classes using design patterns to support VE application modules.
- * Verifying the application behavior on x86_64 with c++_11 libraries(g++) compiler with that of VE based compiler. * Debugging libraries issues in C after they were ported for VE arch.
- * Stubs written mainly in C++ on Visual Studio.
- * OS basic understanding to debug VE Operating system.
- * Role: Lead Engineer
- * Languages used: C and C++ with LINUX
- * Tools Used: Linux with x86_64, Visual Studio

Aricent as Senior Software Engineer Developer Feb 2014 to Apr 2017

Samsung: UT Code Coverage(August 2014 to November 2014)

- * Description
- * Test stubs for code coverage.
- * Debugging issues related to integration of test stubs.
- * Merging and compiling cases from different stubs.
- * Bulls Eye report Generation for code coverage.
- * Stubs written mainly in C++ on Visual Studio.
- * Hands on and training on C++ and Visual Studio.
- * Role: Software Engineer(Fresher)
- * Languages used: C and C++ with LINUX
- * Tools Used: Visual Studio

Nokia Web Tools(December 2014 to July 2015)

- * Description
- * Making a user interface (GUI)/website to automate the handling, monitoring, management & troubleshooting of different critical events on BSCs whose database is maintained on the server.
- * Used SQL small queries and stored procedures to maintain the databases of MySQL.
- * Have used Visual C++ to do the same. Role: Software Engineer(Software Engineer)
- * Languages used: C#, SQL for Apache/Tomcat server

SCAPA(OTN-PI) (August 2015 to August 2016)

- * Description
- * Got the knowledge of LINE CARDS and ROUTE PROCESSORS and the proper understanding that how come they are being handled by IOSXR components.
- * Got the chance to resolve the bugs and issues in the application layer code of OTN framework for both xr-dev and r6112 line-ups.
- * Got the chance to work with bugs in GMPLS handled call-back functions.
- * Resolved bugs in code of channelization from GMPLS or CLI code flow.
- * Resolved the bugs of timing issues i.e. improper call-backs being called with respect to actual flow.
- * Also got the opportunity to make fewer code changes in ODUC2 controller at PI PROCESS (otn_ma) side.
- * Got a nice opportunity to make the enhancements for TTI(Trail Trace Identifier), an important part of OTN framework for ROSCO setup, named as AUTO-TTI feature where two nodes report about each other (their controller name and hostname)
- * Resolved fewer bugs of OTU and ODU component in PI code of IOS-XR.
- * Tracked in and resolved the issues with driver team after the enhancement has been done.

- * Role: Software Engineer(Software Engineer)
- * Languages used: C and C++ with LINUX

Device Driver Test Tool Development(September 2016 to May 2017)

- * Description
- * Participated in making a web tool (PVT) i.e. Platform Validation Tool for ARICENT products team.
- * Main functionality of tool was to test the functionality of drivers in Android that was basically tested for Beagle bone black, generic ARM Boards, Linux Machines, Snapdragon boards, etc.
- * Got the responsibility to write the code mainly for USB(2.0 & 3.0) part. Test code also performed the execution in the same way for OTG ports in Android Phones.
- * Debug USB hub port code using logs.
- * Kernel compilation for ARM and x86 arch.
- * USB has different end points like interrupt, bulk, isochronous. But my code mainly tested transfer speed , reading speed , writing speed , detection of pen drives for all USB bulk end points.
- * Discussed for enhancement and other requirements with our client(QUALCOMM & PANASONIC).
- * Role: Senior Software Engineer(Software Engineer)

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from KIIT in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
С		2018	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
C++		2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Data Structures		2020	2 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
OOPS		2020	2 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
Operating Systems		2016	2 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
Linux		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SQL Server		2015	1 Year(s) 3 Month(s)	
Networking		2017	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
hindi	Proficient			
urdu	Proficient			
english	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General
Physically Challenged: No

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

^{*} Languages used: C and C++ with LINUX

Employment Status: Full time